<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-12T10:52:39+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Quick Overview of EasyGraph: A Comprehensive and Efficient Open-Source Tool for Graph Analysis and Social Computing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2023/08/12/rua.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quick Overview of EasyGraph: A Comprehensive and Efficient Open-Source Tool for Graph Analysis and Social Computing" /><published>2023-08-12T10:18:43+08:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T10:18:43+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2023/08/12/rua</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/jekyll/update/2023/08/12/rua.html"><![CDATA[<p>A graph is a primitive representation of relationships between entities, and it allows for a profound and direct understanding of the associations in the world. Typical applications of graph data include social networks, transaction data, knowledge graphs, transportation systems, biotechnology, and etcetera.Social networks are a specific type of graph data which is built upon the foundation of graph networks and guided by certain sociological theories.</p>

<p>Graph Analysis focuses on analyzing the strength and direction of relationships between entities in graph data, thereby uncovering features and assisting in decision-making.</p>

<p>EasyGraph is an open-source graph analysis package based on the Python language, developed by the MSN team at Fudan University. <strong>Compared to existing open-source libraries focusing on graph analysis such as igraph and NetworkX, EasyGraph offers a more comprehensive set of social network analysis methods grounded in sociological theories.</strong> Its main functionalities include the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>The first open-source library that includes a comprehensive set of structural hole spanner detection methods (for more understanding of the structural hole theory: [Structural Hole Theory in Social Network Analysis: A Review</td>
          <td>IEEE Journals &amp; Magazine</td>
          <td>IEEE Xplore](https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9406195))</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Graph embedding algorithms like DeepWalk, Node2Vec, LINE, SDNE, etc.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Classic network algorithms for community detection, centrality analysis, component analysis, clustering, etc.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Improved runtime efficiency through hybrid programming and parallel computing.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A collection of visualization methods for complex networks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Including various classic datasets.</p>

    <h1 id="easygraphs-structure">EasyGraph’s structure:</h1>

    <p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:674/0*piZO5RtU0jjEoZGy.png" alt="img" /></p>

    <p>​</p>

    <p>With this architecture, EasyGraph can be applied in various domains such as biology, transportation, chemistry, social sciences, ecology, and more for graph data analysis.</p>

    <h1 id="take-a-deeper-look-into-easygraph">Take a deeper look into Easygraph:</h1>

    <p>Github：<a href="https://github.com/easy-graph/Easy-Graph">easy-graph/Easy-Graph: EasyGraph is an open source graph processing library, which covers advanced graph processing methods in structural hole spanners detection, graph embedding and several classic methods. (github.com)</a></p>

    <p>Documentation：<a href="https://easy-graph.github.io/?utm_source=CSDN&amp;utm_medium=article">EasyGraph by FudanMSN (easy-graph.github.io)</a></p>

    <p>Quickly start through Video Tutorials：<a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLcvrOp9f5pLSX9O8Gn4Zmz45VnOq7Pnuh">Tutorials — YouTube</a></p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A graph is a primitive representation of relationships between entities, and it allows for a profound and direct understanding of the associations in the world. Typical applications of graph data include social networks, transaction data, knowledge graphs, transportation systems, biotechnology, and etcetera.Social networks are a specific type of graph data which is built upon the foundation of graph networks and guided by certain sociological theories.]]></summary></entry></feed>